(This drama is related to specific characters, institutions, and groups It has nothing to do with the case and is purely fictitious (I hereby inform you)
(본 드라마는 특정 인물, 기관, 집단과 관련되어 있습니다. 해당 사건과 무관하며 순전히 허구입니다. (본 내용을 알려드립니다)
The prosecution presented defendant Cui Zhexiong with
검찰은 피고인 Cui Zhexiong에게 다음과 같은 사실을 제시했습니다.
common assault
일반적인 공격
Seeking a fine of NT$100,000
벌금 NT$100,000를 요구합니다.
And learn from the defendant Li Dou...
그리고 피고인 Li Dou에게서 배우십시오 ...
(Episode 2)
(에피소드 2)
sorry
미안
Did I say I was going to watch a movie today?
제가 오늘 영화를 보러 간다고 했죠?
I forgot
나는 잊었다
You seem to be too undisciplined lately
요즘 너 너무 예의가 없는 것 같아
Do you want me to cheer you up with my nunchucks?
내가 쌍절곤으로 당신을 응원해줄까요?
One just came now Not one has come yet
지금 막 하나 왔어 아직 한명도 안왔어
You two are so...
너희 둘은 너무...
He should come. Just wait.
그는 와야 해요. 기다리세요.
scared me
겁이 났어
Really
정말로
I can meet you first
먼저 만날 수 있어요
Then who are you going to choose?
그럼 당신은 누구를 선택할 것인가?
Well, I need to think about this again.
글쎄, 이건 다시 생각해볼 필요가 있어.
After all, you need to get along with each other a lot to understand each other.
결국, 서로를 이해하려면 많이 어울려야 합니다.
How long do you need to think about it?
언제까지 생각해야 하나요?
Probably…
아마…
about a year
약 1년
Until then, we can just be friends, okay?
그때까지는 우리 그냥 친구로 지내면 돼요, 그렇죠?
That guy is really brave
그 사람 정말 용감해요
How dare you let my Wu Dingchen pigeon go?
감히 내 Wu Dingchen 비둘기를 놓아주나요?
Could he have forgotten?
그 사람이 잊어버린 게 아닐까?
Forgot
잊어버렸어요
Why do you all have the same virtues?
왜 모두 같은 미덕을 가지고 있습니까?
are you brothers
당신은 형제입니까?
Let's go in by ourselves
우리끼리 들어가자
Don't do this
이러지 마세요
Wait a little longer
조금만 더 기다려
I'm dating you It’s not like I’m dating Tetsuo
나 너랑 데이트 중이야 테츠오랑 사귀는 건 아닌데
Tetsuo doesn’t know yet
테츠오는 아직 몰라
I will tell him today
오늘 그에게 말할게요
The time is almost up. Go in first.
시간이 거의 다 됐어요. 먼저 들어가세요.
This doesn't seem good
이건 좋지 않은 것 같아
Let's go find Tetsuo
테츠오를 찾으러 가자
You wait for me here
넌 여기서 날 기다려
I'll go look around and come back.
좀 둘러보고 돌아올게요.
Hello
안녕하세요
Hello Tetsuo
안녕하세요 테츠오
Brat
녀석
Where did you hide the money?
돈을 어디에 숨겼나요?
money
돈
My home is a bank
우리 집은 은행이에요
If you have the guts, just go to my house and get it, bastard
배짱 있으면 그냥 우리 집에 가서 가져와 새끼야
No matter how big or small the guy is
그 사람이 크든 작든 상관없이
It's so rude to speak to my elder brother
형이랑 얘기하는 게 너무 무례해요
I think you haven't been beaten enough...
내 생각엔 넌 충분히 구타당하지 않은 것 같아...
Tetsuo
테츠오
What are you doing? are you okay
뭐하는 거야? 괜찮아?
you go
너는 가
You go quickly
빨리 가세요
Hello Tetsuo
안녕하세요 테츠오
This is your horse
이것은 당신의 말입니다
She's really scary. Much more powerful than you.
그녀는 정말 무섭습니다. 당신보다 훨씬 더 강력합니다.
Are you gangsters?
당신은 갱스터입니까?
Don't make me call the police. You go away quickly.
경찰에 신고하라고 하지 마세요. 빨리 가세요.
So scary…
너무 무서워…
Tetsuo, let's go
테츠오, 가자
Let's go
가자
Hello
안녕하세요
let me go
날 보내줘
You idle bastards
게으른 놈들아
bitch
개년아
Bastard
놈
No, Tetsuo
아니, 테츠오
No
아니요
Just call the police. You can't do this.
그냥 경찰에 전화하세요. 당신은 이것을 할 수 없습니다.
Brat
녀석
Help
도움말
I thought people who had studied Can't use hands or feet
공부한 사람들인 줄 알았는데 손이나 발을 사용할 수 없음
Don't move
움직이지 마세요
because of you in the future
너 때문에 앞으로도
When I go out, I need to put an iron plate on my stomach first.
외출할 때는 먼저 배에 철판을 올려야 해요.
You dare to point a knife at me next time
다음번엔 감히 나한테 칼을 겨누다니
I will definitely give you a good look
꼭 좋은 모습 보여드리겠습니다
Let's go
가자
Gone
사라짐
are you okay
괜찮아?
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
what to do
무엇을 해야할지
You…
당신은…
That bastard
그 새끼
I want to kill him with my own hands
내 손으로 죽이고 싶다
No, Tetsuo, I'm fine
No, Tetsuo, I'm fine
Don't argue with that kind of person. Let's go call the police.
그런 사람과 논쟁하지 마세요. 경찰에 전화하러 가자.
No, I will give him back double the amount.
아니요, 그 사람에게 두 배의 금액을 돌려주겠습니다.
No, Tetsuo
No, Tetsuo
Douxue is coming soon
Douxue가 곧 옵니다
let's go back
돌아가자
Why? Are you going to complain to me?
왜요? 나한테 불평할 거야?
We are all friends. Why are you doing this?
We are all friends. 왜 이러는 걸까요?
friends
친구
I'm back
나는 돌아왔다
after you school
학교 끝나고
Didn't you go to Tetsuo's school?
테츠오의 학교에 가지 않았나요?
I've been there a few times but he said there's no need to go.
몇 번 가봤지만 갈 필요가 없다고 하더군요.
Tetsuo
테츠오
Otherwise, let's go to the drugstore to buy some medicine for rubbing.
그렇지 않으면 약국에 가서 문지르는 약을 사자.
We…
우리는…
Didn’t you agree to be friends for a year?
1년 동안 친구로 지내기로 약속하지 않았나요?
Isn’t that what you said?
당신이 말한 것이 아닌가요?
You need to get along more to understand each other
서로를 이해하려면 더 많이 친해져야 해
My heart...made its own decision
내 마음이...스스로 결정을 내렸어
ok
알았어
You go
당신은 간다
Tetsuo Douxue is now...
도슈 테츠오는 지금...
My heart says it today…
오늘 내 마음이 그러는데...
don't want to see you
당신을 보고 싶지 않아요
Tetsuo
테츠오
Tetsuo, it's me
테츠오, 나야
I heard you were injured. You had a fight with someone.
부상을 당했다고 들었습니다. 당신은 누군가와 싸웠습니다.
Who can beat me like this?
누가 나를 이렇게 이길 수 있겠는가?
I was injured by my own fall
나는 내가 넘어져서 부상을 입었다
Is the injury serious?
부상이 심각한가요?
let me see
좀 보자
I'm fine
난 괜찮아
You go back
너는 돌아가라
How can it be
어떻게 그럴 수 있니?
Hello
안녕하세요
let me see
좀 보자
Just say I'm fine
그냥 괜찮다고 말해줘
who is
누구야?
Who did it to you?
누가 당신에게 그랬나요?
Who dares to lay hands on me
누가 감히 나에게 손을 대겠는가?
I fell on my own
나 혼자 넘어졌어
Go back quickly
빨리 돌아가라
Mom
엄마
why are you here
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
I'm a little worried about him
그 사람이 조금 걱정돼요
Who is he fighting with?
그는 누구와 싸우고 있습니까?
He said he fell
넘어졌다고 하더군요
do you believe him
당신은 그를 믿나요?
Zhexiong has such a strong self-esteem
Zhexiong은 자존감이 너무 강해요
Even if I get beaten, I will never admit it.
때려도 절대 인정하지 않을 거예요.
Didn't I tell you to go back?
내가 돌아가라고 말하지 않았나요?
Tetsuo
테츠오
it's me
나야
Brother...just went back
형...그냥 돌아갔어
I'm not here to find him
나는 그를 찾으러 여기 온 것이 아니다
I heard you were injured
부상당했다고 들었는데
This is what I bought at the market last time
이건 지난번에 마트에서 샀던 것이에요
It's American
미국식이야
Great for treating bruises and sprains
타박상과 염좌 치료에 좋습니다.
I wiped it once
한번 닦아봤습니다
It won't hurt when I wake up from sleep
자고 일어나면 안 아프겠다.
what are you doing here
여기서 뭐해?
Madam, don’t get me wrong.
부인, 오해하지 마세요.
I heard Tetsuo was injured
테츠오가 부상당했다고 들었어
I have a good ointment at home…
집에 좋은 연고가 있는데...
We also have ointments at home.
집에도 연고가 있어요.
And…
그리고…
Although we are very familiar neighbors
우리는 매우 친숙한 이웃이지만
But it’s so late and you still go in and out of other people’s houses casually
그런데 시간이 너무 늦어서 아직도 남의 집에 아무렇지도 않게 드나들고 있잖아
Isn't that too rude?
너무 무례한 것 아닌가요?
really sorry
정말 미안해
Douxue, you too
듀스 너도 마찬가지야
Don't come to our house so late
우리 집에 너무 늦게 오지 마세요
Yes
예
Let's go
가자
Let go, I will go on my own
놔, 나 혼자 갈게
It hurts my feelings...
기분이 상해요...
younger than me She looks like the wife of a high-ranking official
나보다 어리다 고위공직자의 부인같네요
Speaking of which, who was Tetsuo beaten by?
그러고보니 테츠오는 누구에게 패한 걸까?
When you went to school together This has never happened
같이 학교 다닐 때 이런 일은 일어난 적이 없습니다
Your father wants to send you to Agricultural High School
아버지가 너를 농업고등학교에 보내고 싶어 하신다
I should have stopped him
내가 그를 막았어야 했는데
Mom
엄마
You are now sad because I went to Nonggao
내가 농가오에 갔다고 너 지금 슬퍼하고 있구나
Still sad because Tetsuo was beaten?
테츠오가 맞아서 아직도 슬픈가요?
All sad
모두 슬프다
Really
정말로
I didn't tell you not to come.
오지 말라고는 안 했어요.
I'm not here to go home with you
난 너랑 집에 가려고 여기 온 게 아니야
Dingchen said she must see you tonight
Dingchen이 오늘 밤에 꼭 만나야 한다고 하더군요
She has something to tell you
그 사람이 너한테 할 말이 있어
Meet at the grilled oyster restaurant where we ate
우리가 식사했던 굴구이집에서 만나요
What about you?
당신은 어떻습니까?
I will go there later
나중에 거기로 갈게요
I don’t have the face to see you, Brother Zhongzhong
나는 당신을 볼 얼굴이 없습니다, 종중 형제님
He's really amazing
그는 정말 대단해요
He rejected our nomination
그는 우리의 지명을 거절했다
Do you want to run as a nonpartisan?
무당파로 출마하시겠습니까?
I know it may not be useful though
그래도 유용하지 않을 수도 있다는 걸 알아요
But I will try to persuade him
하지만 나는 그를 설득하려고 노력할 것이다
The family has no money
가족이 돈이 없어요
I still want to run for office as an independent party member.
나는 아직도 무소속 당원으로 출마하고 싶다.
He can make a cooked duck fly Can you persuade him?
그는 요리된 오리를 날게 만들 수 있어요 그를 설득할 수 있나요?
Marry someone who is noble and honorable Thank you for your hard work, Ms. Jiang
고상하고 존귀한 사람과 결혼하라 장 선생님, 노고에 감사드립니다
Okay, you go back
알았어, 넌 돌아가
Take this back too
이것도 다시 가져가세요
No. How can I be embarrassed?
아니요. 어떻게 당황스러울 수 있나요?
Take it back
다시 가져가세요
These…
이것들은…
You saved it with great difficulty Private money
힘들게 구하셨어요 개인돈
Of course, use it at home
물론 집에서도 사용하세요
It's okay I...
괜찮아 난...
Sorry Brother Zhongzhong
미안해요 종중형님
What are the chances of Choi Young-sik being elected?
최영식 당선 가능성은?
I discussed it with people from the CIA
나는 CIA 사람들과 그것에 대해 논의했습니다.
what do they say
그들이 뭐라고 말하나요?
He may get more than 30% of the votes
그는 30% 이상의 득표율을 얻을 수도 있다
(Changing Yeosu starts with people No. 3 Choi Young-sik) It cannot be ruled out that he may be elected first
(여수의 변화는 3인 최영식부터 시작된다) 그가 먼저 당선될 가능성도 배제할 수 없다.
Choi Young-sik… Really?
최영식… 정말요?
He is quite famous locally And have a close relationship with the residents
그는 현지에서 꽤 유명하다. 그리고 주민들과 긴밀한 관계를 맺고
In addition, his father is an independence activist
게다가 아버지가 독립운동가이기도 하고
Have you found his weakness?
그의 약점을 찾았나요?
He doesn't have any corruption or women problems
그는 부패나 여성 문제가 없습니다
If the captain hadn't struck first,
선장이 먼저 공격하지 않았다면,
It will be very nerve-wracking later
나중에 엄청 짜증나겠다
My name is Qi Yingzhuo
내 이름은 Qi Yingzhuo입니다.
You don't want to be expelled from school Go to jail
학교에서 퇴학 당하고 싶지 않은 경우 감옥에 가세요
i was wrong
내가 틀렸어
I won't bully them anymore
나는 더 이상 그들을 괴롭히지 않을 것이다
Really I swear
정말 맹세해요
What I want you to do is another thing
내가 당신에게 바라는 것은 다른 것입니다
You know him?
그 사람 알아요?
know
알고있다
He was talking to a guy he called "Brother" often together
그는 "형제"라고 불리는 남자와 이야기를 나누고 있었습니다. often together
Cui Zhexiong
Cui Zhexiong
Yes
예
You just need to let him hit you a few times.
그가 당신을 몇 번 때리게 놔두기만 하면 됩니다.
It would be better if it sheds some blood
피 좀 흘리면 더 좋을텐데
what
뭐
Really
정말로
Don’t you know me very well? Really?
당신은 나를 잘 모르나요? 정말?
drink so much
drink so much
Drinking capacity is so bad
술자리가 너무 안좋다
Damn it
젠장
what are you doing
뭐하는거야?
Dingchen will not come
Dingchen will not come
And…
그리고…
I know he's the one who hit you
나는 그 사람이 당신을 때린 사람이라는 것을 압니다
Did someone ask you to help me?
누군가 나에게 도움을 요청했나요?
Even if you don't help I have no intention of letting this guy go either.
Even if you don't help 나 역시 이 사람을 놓아줄 생각은 없다.
What? Do you think I will lose?
무엇? 내가 질 것 같아?
Do you think I will lose to this kind of person?
내가 이런 사람한테 질 것 같아?
Please apologize and say you won't bully anyone again.
사과하고 다시는 누구도 괴롭히지 않겠다고 말해주세요.
What a joke
정말 농담이에요
No man can win
No man can win
Just find someone else to help, coward.
도와줄 다른 사람을 찾으세요, 겁쟁이님.
Hello Qi Yingzhuo
Hello Qi Yingzhuo
You guy...
You guy...
OK
괜찮은
Brother, don't interfere
형님, 방해하지 마세요
Tetsuo
테츠오
OK
괜찮은
I've already taught him a lesson for you
나는 이미 그에게 당신을 위한 교훈을 가르쳤습니다.
I told you not to interfere
방해하지 말라고 했잖아
What do you want
당신은 무엇을 원하나요
I'll forget it if I get beaten
맞으면 잊어버릴 거야
This guy…
이놈…
This guy hit Dingchen
Error 504 (Server Error)!!1504.That’s an error.There was an error. Please try again later.That’s all we know.
I can't even forgive him
나는 그 사람을 용서할 수도 없어요.
Of course you can't forgive him
물론 그 사람을 용서할 수는 없지
You are not...
당신은 그렇지 않습니다 ...
Have you decided to date?
데이트하기로 결정하셨나요?
Did he really hit Dingchen?
그가 정말로 Dingchen을 때렸나요?
Hello Qi Yingzhuo
안녕 치잉주오
It's a good thing you didn't bring anyone with you
아무도 데려오지 않아서 다행이야
Let's challenge each other
서로 도전해보자
I'll give you money if you win, but...
이기면 돈을 주겠지만...
If you lose, you will die here today
지면 오늘 여기서 죽는다
Do you know
당신은 알고 있나요
Stop talking nonsense
말도 안되는 소리 그만해
Brat let me go
애새끼 날 보내줘
You can't beat me at all
넌 나를 전혀 이길 수 없어
Come on Get up, brat
어서 해봐요 일어나, 새끼야
Get up quickly
빨리 일어나
Don't come here
여기 오지 마세요
If you dare to come here
감히 여기까지 오신다면
Let's break off the relationship
관계를 끊자
The most embarrassing guy in the world
세상에서 제일 부끄러운 놈
The guy who pretends to be powerful
강한 척 하는 남자
Don't act cool in front of that girl again.
다시는 그 여자 앞에서 쿨한 척 하지 마세요.
Is this enough?
이 정도면 충분합니까?
I can go now
이제 갈 수 있어요
Tetsuo
테츠오
Get up and fight me again
일어나서 다시 나랑 싸워
I'll wake you up
내가 깨워줄게
Qi Yingzhuo, wake up
치잉주오, 일어나요
Qi Yingzhuo
치 잉주오
What...what's wrong
Error 504 (Server Error)!!1504.That’s an error.There was an error. Please try again later.That’s all we know.
Is he... is he dead?
그 사람... 죽었나요?
(New Inner Harbor Hospital)
(뉴 이너 하버 병원)
Hello Qi Yingzhuo
안녕 치잉주오
Qi Yingzhuo
치 잉주오
The hospital contacted Lishui Police Department
병원은 리수이 경찰서에 연락했습니다.
It was said that two students took the injured Qi Yingzhuo Carry to the hospital
부상당한 Qi Yingzhuo를 두 명의 학생이 데려 갔다고합니다. 병원으로 운반
Qi Yingzhuo is currently unconscious
Qi Yingzhuo는 현재 의식을 잃은 상태입니다.
He won't die
그는 죽지 않을 것이다
Brother, people don’t die that easily, right?
형님, 사람은 그렇게 쉽게 죽지 않죠?
he won't die
그 사람은 죽지 않을 거야
He will definitely survive
그 사람은 반드시 살아남을 거야
Tetsuo
테츠오
Let's turn ourselves in
스스로 입장하자
Anyway, even if he is alive We also have to pay the price
어쨌든 그 사람이 살아있다고 해도 우리도 대가를 치러야 해
Brother, I did nothing wrong
형님 저는 잘못한 게 없어요
I was in self-defense
나는 정당방위를 하고 있었다
So
그래서
We told the police everything
우리는 경찰에게 모든 것을 말했어요
No
아니요
I won't go
나는 가지 않을 것이다
Also
또한
is this my fault
is this my fault
Did I ask you to bring Qi Yingzhuo to me?
Qi Yingzhuo를 나에게 데려오라고 요청했나요?
It was you who lied to me
나에게 거짓말을 한 건 바로 너였어
Said Dingchen wanted to see me
Dingchen이 나를 보고 싶다고 했어
You know I won't let him go And brought him to see me
내가 그 사람을 놓아주지 않을 거라는 걸 알잖아 그리고 나를 만나러 그를 데려왔어
So it's all your fault
So it's all your fault
Did I say something wrong?
내가 뭔가 잘못 말했나요?
That's right
그렇죠
it's all my fault
다 내 잘못이야
Wrong
틀렸어
I'm crazy
나는 미쳤어
I was the one who stoned him
그 사람에게 돌을 던진 건 나였어
You just...
당신은 단지 ...
Just want to help me
Just want to help me
right
맞아
Brother
형제
I'm so scared
너무 무서워요
if that guy dies
if that guy dies
I'd be thrown in jail for murder
살인죄로 감옥에 갇힐 뻔
My dad doesn’t have to elect a member of parliament anymore. Our family will be ruined
우리 아빠는 더 이상 국회의원을 선출할 필요가 없어요. 우리 가족은 망할 거야
The mother who pinned all her hopes on me Will definitely fall ill
나에게 모든 희망을 걸었던 어머니 틀림없이 병이 들 것이다
Brother, what should I do now?
형님, 이제 어떻게 해야 하나요?
what should i do
나는 무엇을 해야 합니까?
Brother
형제
Brother, can you save me once?
형님, 저 한 번만 구해 주실 수 있나요?
could you tell the police It was you who hit Qi Yingzhuo with a stone
경찰에 말해줄래? Qi Yingzhuo를 돌로 친 것은 당신이었습니다
Tetsuo
테츠오
Brother
형제
Brother…
형…
save me
나를 구해줘
If you help me this time
이번에 도와주시면
I will be responsible for the rest of your life
당신의 남은 인생은 제가 책임지겠습니다.
Wrong
틀렸어
I will work hard to get ahead
앞으로 열심히 노력하겠습니다
Live for you all my life
내 평생을 당신을 위해 살아요
I know you always let me go
당신이 항상 나를 놓아준다는 걸 알아요
I promise that I will
나는 그럴 것이라고 약속한다.
I will definitely live for you
난 반드시 당신을 위해 살아갈 거예요
Brother
형제
Just save me once
한번만 구해줘
why should i help you
내가 왜 당신을 도와야 하나요?
It was obviously you who did it
그런 짓을 한 건 분명 너였어
Why should I take the blame for you?
왜 내가 당신의 책임을 져야 합니까?
My dad too
우리 아빠도
me too
나도
Live like a slave to your family all my life
평생 네 가족의 노예처럼 살아라
why did this happen
왜 이런 일이 일어났는가?
I want to help you take the blame
나는 당신이 비난을 받도록 돕고 싶습니다.
your life matters
당신의 인생은 중요하다
Isn't my life important?
내 목숨이 중요하지 않은가?
your life is human life
당신의 인생은 인간의 삶입니다
Is my life worse than that of a pig or a dog?
내 인생은 돼지나 개보다 더 나쁜가?
Douxue
두쉬
What are you doing there if you don't go to sleep?
안 자면 거기서 뭐해?
uncle
삼촌
If something happens to Tetsuo
테츠오에게 무슨 일이 생기면
Not just him, his father and me
그 사람뿐만 아니라 그 사람 아버지와 나까지
Something happens to our whole family.
우리 가족 모두에게 무슨 일이 일어났습니다.
Please save him
그를 구해주세요
It's just your son now
지금은 그냥 당신 아들이에요
You can save our family
당신은 우리 가족을 구할 수 있습니다
madam
부인
I never refused any of your requests
난 네 부탁을 단 한번도 거절한 적이 없어
But this time…
하지만 이번에는…
I can't promise you
약속할 수 없어
How could you sacrifice Douxue to save Tetsuo?
테츠오를 구하기 위해 어떻게 Douxue를 희생할 수 있습니까?
uncle
삼촌
As long as his father is elected
그의 아버지가 당선되는 한
I'll get him out of jail as soon as possible
최대한 빨리 그 사람을 감옥에서 꺼내줄게요
I will definitely do that
나는 반드시 그렇게 할 것이다
I will hire the best lawyer for him
나는 그를 위해 최고의 변호사를 고용할 것이다
uncle
삼촌
If his father loses the election, our family will be doomed.
그의 아버지가 선거에서 지면 우리 가족은 파멸에 이를 것입니다.
He has to be elected before we can be saved
우리가 구원받기 전에 그분이 선택되어야 합니다
Please save my son, uncle
내 아들, 삼촌을 구해주세요
Save my son, uncle.
내 아들을 구해주세요, 삼촌.
save him This…
그를 구해줘 이…
uncle
삼촌
Don't go
가지 마세요
Don't go, uncle
가지 마세요, 삼촌
Please save my son
내 아들을 살려주세요
uncle…
삼촌…
let me go
날 보내줘
No…
아니…
uncle…
삼촌…
i was wrong
내가 틀렸어
Please save me once
한번만 살려주세요
uncle
삼촌
you kid
너 꼬마
Why do you do that?
왜 그러는 걸까요?
why would you do that
왜 그런 짓을 하겠니?
uncle
삼촌
Please...
제발...
Please save me once uncle
한번만 살려주세요 삼촌
Douxue
두쉬
what are you doing
뭐하는거야?
You must have done something wrong
당신은 뭔가 잘못한 게 틀림없어요
My son is definitely not that kind of person
내 아들은 절대 그런 사람이 아니야
You go and investigate and come back.
가서 조사하고 다시 오세요.
We need to take him back to the bureau to investigate first.
먼저 그를 조사국으로 데려가서 조사해야 합니다.
Please wait patiently
참을성있게 기다려주십시오
Why are you investigating him?
왜 그 사람을 조사하는 거죠?
Otherwise, you can ask the people in the village.
그렇지 않으면 마을 사람들에게 물어볼 수도 있습니다.
Who is better at reading than Douxue? A better child?
Douxue보다 독서를 더 잘하는 사람은 누구입니까? 더 나은 아이?
If you keep making trouble again, we'll charge you with obstructing official business. Take you back to the bureau
계속해서 문제를 일으키시면 공무방해죄로 고소하겠습니다. 당신을 다시 사무국으로 데려가세요
OK
알았어
you take me away
당신은 나를 데려가
Take me away
날 데려가줘
I don't allow you to take away my child
당신이 내 아이를 데려가는 걸 허락하지 않아요
I'm not allowed
나는 허락되지 않는다
Douxue, please tell me it wasn’t you.
Douxue, 당신이 아니었다고 말해주세요.
Tell me you are innocent
당신은 결백하다고 말해주세요
I'm really going crazy
정말 미칠 것 같아
Hello, Patrolman Kim, Patrolman Park
안녕하세요, 김순경님, 박순경님.
What are you doing?
뭐하는 거야?
So annoying
너무 짜증나
Douxue
두쉬
what's going on
무슨 일이야?
Who is this lady?
이 여자는 누구입니까?
Not you
너 말고
you are not that kind of person
당신은 그런 사람이 아니야
Li Douxue
리두수에
Look into my eyes and tell me
내 눈을 보고 말해봐
you are not that kind of person
당신은 그런 사람이 아니야
right
맞아
It's obviously not you
분명 당신은 아닌데
Okay, let me borrow it
알았어, 빌려줄게
Wait
잠깐
Li Douxue…
리두수에…
Douxue…
듀스…
Tetsuo
테츠오
Tetsuo, you also know
테츠오, 너도 알지?
Douxue is not that kind of person
두슈는 그런 사람이 아니야
Cui Zhexiong Li Douxue
Cui Zhexiong Li Douxue
answer me quickly
빨리 대답해줘
Need to drive
운전이 필요하다
Wait
잠깐
You two, wait.
너희 둘, 잠깐만.
Douxue
두쉬
Douxue…
듀스…
Dou Xue
두설
You…
당신은…
don't forgive dad
아빠를 용서하지 마세요
Douxue
두쉬
You can't take my child away
당신은 내 아이를 데려갈 수 없어요
What did he do wrong?
그가 무슨 잘못을 했나요?
Mom
엄마
Douxue… Mom…
듀스… 엄마…
Douxue
두쉬
You're not that kind of person
당신은 그런 사람이 아니에요
take me away
나를 데려가 줘
You are not allowed to take away my child
당신은 내 아이를 빼앗을 수 없습니다
What? His friend turned himself in?
무엇? 그 친구가 자수했다고요?
Yes, a young man named Li Douxue
네, Li Douxue라는 청년이 있어요.
He said it was because he saw Cui Cheol-woong
최철웅을 봤기 때문이라고 하더군요
Always beaten by Qi Yingzhuo
항상 Qi Yingzhuo에게 맞았습니다.
That’s why I stoned Qi Yingzhuo
그래서 Qi Yingzhuo를 돌로 쳤어
No
아니요
It’s useless for Lee Doo-hak to be sentenced
이두학이 형을 선고받아도 소용없다
before the election ends delay the trial as much as possible
선거가 끝나기 전에 재판을 최대한 연기하다
And said Choi Young-sik’s son was an accomplice
그리고 최영식 아들이 공범이라고 하더군요
I know
알아요
-Choi Young-sik… -Golden King Root…
-최영식… -황금왕뿌리…
-Please vote for number two
- 2번에게 투표해주세요.
-Please vote for number three -Golden King Root…
- 3번에게 투표해주세요. -황금왕뿌리…
Everyone
모두
We must overthrow the dictatorship this time
이번엔 독재를 타도해야 한다
into the arms of democracy and freedom Everyone, do you think it’s right?
민주주의와 자유의 품으로 여러분, 그게 맞다고 생각하시나요?
Yes
예
thank you all
모두 감사합니다
Yes thank you all
네 모두 감사합니다
Choi Young-sik, the father of the murderer, should withdraw from the election
살인범 아버지 최영식, 출마하라
Choi Young-sik, who raised a murderer, should withdraw from the election.
살인범을 키운 최영식은 총선에서 물러나야 한다.
Everyone, I deeply regret that this happened.
여러분, 이런 일이 일어난 것을 깊이 후회합니다.
But my son definitely doesn’t…
하지만 우리 아들은 절대 그렇지 않아요...
Withdraw
철수
Withdraw…
철수…
Okay…
알았어…
(No. 3 Choi Young-sik)
(3번 최영식)
(Choi Young-sik)
(최영식)
Didn't you say that Tetsuo was an eyewitness?
테츠오가 목격자라고 하지 않았나요?
Didn't you say he didn't fight with anyone?
그 사람은 누구와도 싸우지 않았다고 하지 않았나요?
why lie to me
왜 나한테 거짓말을 해?
He did get into fights
그 사람은 실제로 싸웠어요
But Tetsuo was the one who was beaten
하지만 당한 사람은 테츠오였다.
Douxue, on the other hand, saw Tetsuo being cheered up and couldn't help but
반면 두스는 테츠오가 기운을 내는 것을 보고 어쩔 수 없었다.
That's why I hit that person on the head with a stone.
그래서 나는 그 사람의 머리를 돌로 때렸습니다.
Wrong…
틀렸어…
The Douxue I know is not that kind of person
내가 아는 두수는 그런 사람이 아니다
Could it be...
그럴 수도 있지...
Is Tetsuo the one who caused the trouble?
문제를 일으킨 사람이 테츠오인가?
Husband
남편
Wife, are you hiding something from me?
부인, 나한테 숨기는 게 있나요?
Please explain it clearly to me
나에게 명확하게 설명해주세요.
young master
젊은 주인
Douxue told me everything about that day.
Douxue는 나에게 그날의 모든 것을 말해주었다.
He said he did it
자기가 했다고 하더군요
Really?
정말요?
Yes
예
I will never lie to you
나는 결코 당신에게 거짓말을하지 않을 것입니다
Who is that...
그 사람은 누구입니까?
Who did you provoke first?
누구를 먼저 도발했나요?
This...this...
이거...이거...
Brother please tell me
형님 좀 알려주세요
It was indeed Tetsuo who provoked others first.
먼저 다른 사람을 도발한 것은 테츠오였다.
My child is indeed involved in the case
내 아이가 실제로 이 사건에 연루되어 있습니다.
Let everyone run for me during this time
이 시간 동안 모두가 나를 위해 달려가도록 해주세요
Thank you all for your hard work
모두들 노고에 감사드립니다
I don’t have the face to see you all
다 볼 얼굴은 없어
I'm really sorry
정말 미안해요
No
아니요
You cannot withdraw
철회할 수 없습니다.
It was Doxue who beat people to death, not Tetsuo
사람을 때려죽인 것은 테츠오가 아니라 독스였다.
and
그리고
Even if you can't be elected in first place
1순위에 당선되지 못하더라도
Can also be elected in second place
2순위로 선출될 수도 있음
everything is over
모든 것이 끝났습니다
A liar like me How can you be loyal to your country?
나 같은 거짓말쟁이 어떻게 조국에 충성할 수 있습니까?
It's not over yet. You can't give up just yet.
아직 끝나지 않았습니다. 아직은 포기할 수 없습니다.
Wife
아내
Do you know how much we spent campaigning?
우리가 캠페인에 얼마나 돈을 썼는지 아세요?
If you withdraw now
지금 탈퇴하면
lumber mill and all the fields Everything will come to naught
제재소와 모든 밭 모든 것이 물거품이 될 것이다
You…
당신은…
Have you even mortgaged your land?
심지어 땅을 저당잡았나요?
That's right, I did it to get you elected Betting on my life
그래, 난 널 당선시키려고 그랬어 내 인생에 베팅하세요
If you withdraw now
지금 탈퇴하면
Our family will be completely destroyed
우리 가족은 완전히 멸망할 것이다
Why is he a public defender?
그가 국선 변호인인 이유는 무엇입니까?
Didn't Tetsuo's father say Will you help Douxue find a good lawyer?
테츠오의 아버지가 말하지 않았나요? Douxue가 좋은 변호사를 찾을 수 있도록 도와주시겠어요?
Douxue's father refused
Douxue의 아버지는 거절했습니다.
The prosecution presented defendant Cui Zhexiong with
검찰은 피고인 Cui Zhexiong에게 다음과 같은 사실을 제시했습니다.
common assault
일반적인 공격
Seeking a fine of NT$100,000
벌금 NT$100,000를 요구합니다.
and learned from the defendant Li Dou
피고인 Li Dou에게서 배웠습니다.
According to the crime of injury causing death
상해치사죄에 따르면
Seeking a prison sentence of three to five years
징역 3~5년을 구형한다
How could this happen...
어떻게 이런 일이 일어날 수 있었을까...
Defender, please make your final argument.
변호인님, 마지막 변론을 해주시기 바랍니다.
Defendant, have you reflected deeply?
피고인님, 깊이 반성하셨나요?
Yes
예
Dear presiding judge
존경하는 재판장님께
The defendant said he had deeply reflected on
피고인은 깊이 반성했다고 한다.
What to do…
무엇을 해야할지…
Sentencing now
지금 선고 중
What kind of father are you?
당신은 어떤 아버지인가요?
Can you still be called a father like this?
아직도 이렇게 아버지라고 부를 수 있나요?
Why not let him get a good lawyer?
그에게 좋은 변호사를 선임하게 놔두는 건 어떨까요?
Why do you
왜 당신은
You also know very well the current situation of the young master’s family.
당신도 젊은 스승님 가족의 현재 상황을 잘 알고 계십니다.
Besides, if you commit a crime, you should be punished.
게다가 범죄를 저지르면 처벌을 받아야 합니다.
How heartbroken the parents of their child must be
아이를 키우는 부모는 얼마나 마음이 아플까요?
How could I shamelessly Are you asking for a commutation of his sentence?
내가 어떻게 뻔뻔하게 그의 형량을 감형해 달라는 겁니까?
Douxue Li Douxue
두쉬 리 두쉬
I didn't kill the person
나는 사람을 죽이지 않았다
Hello…
안녕하세요…
Hey... wake up
이봐... 일어나
This man is dying
이 사람이 죽어가고 있어요
Call an ambulance quickly
빨리 구급차를 불러주세요
Hurry up
서둘러
(Friendly Hospital)
(친절한 병원)
(Four years later)
(4년 후)
(Gwangju Transfer Station)
(광주환승역)
Dingchen
딩첸
Cui Zhexiong
추이 저시옹
have you seen this movie
이 영화 봤어?
Not yet
아직은 아님
(Flower of the Equator) What about this one?
(적도의 꽃) 이건 어때요?
I haven’t watched that one yet.
나는 아직 그것을 보지 못했습니다.
Hey, don't you have a girlfriend?
아, 여자친구 없나요?
Why is it a movie that everyone has seen? Just you haven't seen it
왜 모두가 본 영화일까요? 단지 당신이 그것을 보지 못했을 뿐이죠
That is to say
즉,
Come to my theater
내 극장으로 오세요
Sister, I let you Free admission from the screening room to the cinema
언니, 허락했어요 상영실에서 영화관까지 무료 입장
Free movies are great
무료 영화는 훌륭해요
However
그러나
Why didn't you tell me
왜 나한테 말하지 않았어?
Is it about my dad’s death?
아버지의 죽음에 관한 것인가요?
What makes you special when you come back from Seoul How sorry
서울에서 돌아오면 당신을 특별하게 만드는 것은 무엇입니까? 정말 미안해
It must have been very hard for you at that time
그 때 많이 힘들었을 텐데
sorry
미안
As a friend, I should be by your side
친구로서 네 옆에 있어야 해
I'm fine
난 괜찮아
My relatives also helped me a lot
친척들도 많이 도와줬어요
By the way, today is not a holiday
그런데 오늘은 공휴일이 아니다
how come you come back
어떻게 돌아왔어?
I came back to pay homage to my father
아버지께 경의를 표하기 위해 돌아왔습니다
Yeah, it’s about this time, right?
응, 이때쯤이지?
The experiences of both of us are similar.
우리 둘의 경험은 비슷해요.
No, you are a college student
아니요, 당신은 대학생입니다
And I'm a theater owner who's on leave from school
그리고 저는 학교를 휴학한 극장주입니다
You want to be the boss It may take 20 years
당신은 보스가되고 싶어 20년은 걸릴지도
Where's Brother Douxue?
Douxue 형제는 어디 있나요?
I haven't heard this name for a long time.
나는 이 이름을 오랫동안 듣지 못했습니다.
Should I say that he disappeared like a gust of wind?
돌풍처럼 사라졌다고 해야 하나?
What about you? You should have contacted him, right?
당신은 어때요? 그 사람한테 연락했어야지, 그렇지?
I didn't meet him either
나도 그 사람을 만나지 않았어
How could it be
어떻게 그럴 수 있니?
Aren't you two like brothers?
둘이 형제같지 않나요?
He always refused me visits in prison
그는 항상 내 감옥 방문을 거부했습니다.
Besides, my current situation It's not suitable to meet him either
게다가 내 현재 상황은 그 사람을 만나는 것도 적합하지 않아
What's going on with you?
무슨 일이야?
It's better to catch the spy that way.
그런 식으로 스파이를 잡는 것이 낫습니다.
Let’s watch the Dingchen movie next time
다음에는 딩첸 영화를 보자
You must pretend you don’t know me
넌 나를 모르는 척 해야 해
what
뭐
catch that guy
그 사람을 잡아라
Hey, catch that guy
야 저 사람 좀 잡아봐
You got promoted
당신은 승진했습니다
Are you going to Seoul after that?
그 후에 서울로 가시나요?
Yeah, I'll be on reserve duty soon.
응, 나 곧 예비군이 될 거야.
How could it be?
어떻게 그럴 수 있니?
I heard that the commander is very caring about you.
지휘관님이 당신을 매우 배려하고 계시다고 들었습니다.
I'm tired of wandering around all my life
평생 방황하느라 지쳤어
The current situation is not as good as it used to be
현재 상황은 예전만큼 좋지 않다.
The commander always gives me other tasks.
지휘관님은 항상 나에게 다른 임무를 주십니다.
what task
어떤 작업
I'll tell you later
나중에 말해줄게
Wait until I go to Seoul I won’t be able to see you often
내가 서울 갈 때까지 기다려 자주 볼 수는 없을 것 같아요
You need to cheer up
힘내세요
If you have any difficulties, just tell me
힘든 일 있으면 나한테 말해.
OK
알았어
(Do not buy tickets from scalpers who disrupt social order)
(사회질서를 어지럽히는 암표상으로부터 티켓을 구매하지 마세요)
(Gwangju Soonyang Theater)
(광주순양극장)
(God is also crazy)
(신도 미쳤어요)
Boss, you are back from Seoul
사장님, 서울에서 돌아오셨어요
Are there many guests coming to watch the movie?
영화를 보러 오는 손님이 많이 오나요?
As you can see, every movie ticket is sold out
보시다시피 모든 영화 티켓이 매진되었습니다.
The audience came in endless streams
관객들이 끝없이 몰려들었다
"Raiders of the Lost Ark" box-office success
'레이더즈 오브 더 로스트아크' 흥행 성공
As long as it's a Hollywood movie
헐리우드 영화인 만큼
All were a hit
모두 대박이 났어요
Brat, that's an African movie, right?
형, 그거 아프리카 영화 맞죠?
But the film is too damaged
근데 필름이 너무 손상됐어요
It takes about 10 minutes to cut it off
자르는데 10분정도 걸리네요
When shown like this How much length will be left in the movie?
이렇게 표시되면 영화의 길이는 얼마나 남을까요?
109 minutes movie If you cut off 20 minutes
109분짜리 영화 20분을 끊으면
About 90 minutes left
약 90분 남았습니다
Will the audience still understand the plot this way?
청중이 여전히 이런 식으로 줄거리를 이해할 수 있을까요?
Don't cut too much
너무 많이 자르지 마세요
Cut as much as you can
최대한 잘라주세요
I know
알아요
Gao Standing Committee Oh my god
가오 상임위원회 맙소사
You're here again
당신은 또 여기 있어요
I must get the film today
나 오늘 영화 꼭 사야 해
What's going on with this girl?
이 소녀에게 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요?
Who is this aunt?
이 이모는 누구예요?
If you don't want to get hurt, just get out of the way first
상처받기 싫으면 먼저 비켜라
This girl is really
이 여자는 정말
get out of my way
내 길에서 비켜줘
Sorry let's go
미안 가자
Okay, now you don’t have to spend money on ads.
좋아요, 이제 광고에 돈을 쓸 필요가 없습니다.
The theater will be in the news tomorrow
내일 극장 뉴스에 나올 거예요
what are you doing
뭐하는거야?
Is your nose blocked? Don’t you smell the pungent smell?
코가 막혔나요? 톡 쏘는 냄새가 나지 않나요?
are you crazy
너 미쳤어?
Yeah, I'm just crazy
응, 난 그냥 미쳤어
I'm talking to you properly, but you can't listen.
내가 제대로 말을 하고 있는데 넌 듣지를 못하는구나.
You'd have to go crazy, wouldn't you?
당신은 미쳐야 할 것입니다, 그렇죠?
Oh my god, why don't you take that match away?
맙소사, 그 성냥을 가져가는 게 어때요?
Do you want to give me the film or not?
나에게 그 영화를 줄 것인가, 말 것인가?
Oops, it looks like the match is wet.
이런, 성냥이 젖은 것 같습니다.
You use this
당신은 이것을 사용
This lighter should light easily
이 라이터는 쉽게 불이 붙을 것입니다
It's made in the United States
미국에서 만들어졌네요
you crazy woman
미친 여자야
Do you want to give me the film?
나에게 영화를 주고 싶나요?
(Boss Che Jinyu)
(최진위 사장님)
It turns out you are Nanhai Theater Boss Wu’s daughter
알고보니 남해극장 우 사장의 딸
I heard your father passed away
네 아버지가 돌아가셨다고 들었어
I was in Seoul at the time
나는 그때 서울에 있었다
I'm really sorry that I couldn't be there to express my condolences.
현장에 참석해 조의를 표하지 못해서 정말 죄송합니다.
Gao Standing Committee yes
가오 상임위원회 응
Have you gone to express condolences?
애도를 표하러 가셨나요?
Well... I was busy working at that time...
뭐... 그땐 일하느라 바빠서...
That's it
그게 다야
After all, Executive Director Gao is a very busy man.
결국 가오 전무이사는 매우 바쁜 사람이다.
what you want to say is
당신이 말하고 싶은 것은
The buyout price of "God is Crazy" Your theater only paid 50%
'신은 미쳤다' 인수 가격 귀하의 극장은 50%만 지불했습니다.
Originally, the balance had to be paid before today.
원래 잔액은 오늘 이전에 지불되어야 했습니다.
But your money is a little tight So I have to wait until the movie is released in Lishui to pay it off
하지만 돈이 좀 부족해요 그래서 영화가 리수이에서 개봉될 때까지 기다려야 갚을 수 있어요
Is that what you mean?
그게 무슨 뜻인가요?
Yes
예
Gao Standing Committee
가오 상임위원회
at our publisher here Has this ever happened?
여기 우리 출판사에서 이런 일이 일어난 적이 있나요?
This is something that has never happened before or since.
이는 이전에도 이후에도 일어난 적이 없는 일이다.
Don't be pretentious to me
나한테 잘난척 하지마
Got it
알았어요
Miss, what should we do?
아가씨, 우리는 어떻게 해야 할까요?
It seems a little difficult
좀 어려울 듯
Can you lend me that lighter just now?
지금 그 라이터 좀 빌려주실 수 있나요?
Oh my God, this guy...
맙소사, 이 사람...
Gao Standing Committee
가오 상임위원회
yes
응
After this movie is over
이 영화가 끝난 후
Just give her the "God Is Crazy" film
그냥 그녀에게 "신은 미쳤다" 영화를 보여주세요
what
뭐
I asked you to give it to her
나는 당신에게 그것을 그녀에게 주라고 요청했습니다
ok boss
알았어 보스
Boss, thank you very much...
사장님, 정말 감사합니다...
I will never forget this kindness
나는 이 친절을 결코 잊지 않을 것이다.
You go
당신은 간다
OK thank you
알았어 고마워
Boss, why did you do such an abnormal thing?
사장님, 왜 이렇게 이상한 짓을 하신 겁니까?
Brat
녀석
Anyway, that broken film If you sell it to someone, you’ll get a 20% discount.
어쨌든 그 깨진 필름 다른 사람에게 판매하면 20% 할인을 받을 수 있습니다.
Plus we didn’t go to the bereaved family to express our condolences. Not living up to the principles of being a human being
게다가 우리는 유족에게 조의를 표하러 가지도 않았습니다. 인간으로서의 원칙을 지키지 못하고
So I have to discount another 30%
그래서 30%를 더 할인해야 해요
It's okay if we don't pay the final payment.
최종 지불금을 지불하지 않아도 괜찮습니다.
Are you still a human being?
당신은 아직도 인간입니까?
Really Oh my god...it hurts
정말로 맙소사... 아파요
And I was clearly on the books two years ago
그리고 나는 2년 전에는 분명히 책 속에 있었어
I saw 50,000 yuan as a memorial gift from Boss Wu.
우보스의 기념 선물로 50,000위안을 봤습니다.
You swallowed that money, right?
그 돈을 삼켰지?
boss
보스
You brat
이 개자식아
It hurts...
아프다...
(Lishui Nanhai Theater)
(리수이 난하이 극장)
boss
보스
You are finally here
당신은 마침내 여기에 있습니다
Why is uncle sitting here?
삼촌은 왜 여기 앉아 계시나요?
(Boss Wu Dingchen)
(우딩첸 사장)
Because the chair is very comfortable
의자가 너무 편하기 때문에
I'll just sit back and watch for a while
그냥 잠시 앉아서 지켜볼게
Only capable people can be bosses
유능한 사람만이 사장이 될 수 있다
Just sitting in the boss's seat Can I be the boss?
그냥 사장님 자리에 앉아서 내가 사장이 될 수 있을까?
why do you say that
왜 그런 말을 해?
How hard Dingchen worked to save the theater
Dingchen이 극장을 구하기 위해 얼마나 열심히 일했는지
So is there any rescue?
그럼 구조는 있나요?
(Boss Wu Dingchen) I got the "God Is Crazy" film
(우딩첸 사장) 나 '신은 미쳤다' 영화를 봤어
Then you can repay part of the debt
그러면 빚의 일부를 갚을 수 있습니다.
Please leave
떠나주세요
Partial debt? How much is that?
부분 부채? 그게 얼마죠?
Have you looked at the account books carefully?
장부를 자세히 살펴 보셨나요?
Just the money your dad took away That’s 50 million won
그냥 아빠가 가져가신 돈이에요 5천만원이에요
Whether it’s 5,000 won or 100 million won I will repay it
5,000원이든 1억 원이든 내가 갚아줄게
please leave
떠나주세요
Who are you yelling at?
누구한테 소리 지르는 거야?
Even if I say now that this theater is mine You have nothing to do with me either
지금 이 극장은 내 것이라고 말해도 너도 나랑 아무 상관 없어
Wife, she said she would pay off the debt
아내가 빚을 갚겠다고 하더군요
We are not loan sharks
우리는 사채업자가 아닙니다
How can this happen between family members?
어떻게 가족들 사이에 이런 일이 일어날 수 있나요?
You don't know where that money came from
그 돈이 어디서 왔는지 넌 모르잖아
My dad gave all his property to my brother
아버지가 전 재산을 동생에게 물려주셨는데
That money means I won’t eat or drink Work hard
그 돈은 내가 먹지도 마시지도 않겠다는 뜻이야 열심히 일해라
Money earned through hard work
열심히 일해서 얻은 돈
That’s why you work so hard Ask me for interest
그래서 넌 그렇게 열심히 일해 나에게 관심을 요청하세요.
what did you say
뭐라고 했어?
The money I gave you before It’s already more than the principal
아까 줬던 돈 벌써 교장 선생님보다 많아
Anyway, this theater has been mortgaged
어쨌든 이 극장은 저당 잡혔어
If I don’t pay for it in the future,
앞으로 갚지 않으면
Just take the theater away
그냥 극장을 없애버려
But now please get out of here
하지만 이제 제발 여기서 나가주세요
You are really rude
당신은 정말 무례해요
good
좋아
If you can't pay it back this year
올해 안에 갚지 못하면
This theater will become mine
이 극장은 내 것이 될 거야
Okay, let's go back
알았어, 돌아가자
Those who are in debt dare to speak loudly
빚진 사람은 감히 큰 소리로 말한다.
What’s wrong with today’s society?
요즘 사회에 무슨 문제가 있나요?
Scammers and debtors are so arrogant
사기꾼과 채무자는 너무 오만합니다
Dingchen, let’s go first.
딩첸, 먼저 가자.
So delicious
너무 맛있어
Where is Tetsuo?
테츠오는 어디 있어?
I waited for a long time at the bus stop
버스 정류장에서 오랫동안 기다렸어요
But I didn't see him
하지만 나는 그를 보지 못했어요
What's going on
무슨 일이야?
He clearly said he was coming back
분명히 돌아오겠다고 하더군요
He'll be fine
그 사람은 괜찮을 거야
The last bus will arrive in an hour
마지막 버스는 한 시간 후에 도착할 거예요
I'll go to the bus stop and wait for him
나는 버스 정류장에 가서 그를 기다릴 것이다
The weather is very cold at night
밤에는 날씨가 많이 춥네요
Come into the house quickly
빨리 집에 들어와
I'm leaving
나는 떠난다
听说你父亲过世了
听说你父亲过世了
你大学也只念到一半就休学了
你大school也只念到一半就休school了
贞玉全都跟我说了
贞玉전체도시 跟我说了
原来是这样
来是这样
我爸本来就久病在身了
我爸本来就久病재身了
所以我一直都有心理准备
所以我一直TU유심리准备
我没事 我真的没事
나의 没事 나의 没事
定辰 你以后别再来了
정의 你以后别再来了
发生什么事了吗
发生什么事了吗
我…没有信心
나는…
我们到此为止吧
我们到此为止吧
这是什么意思
这是什么意思
你一定可以重新再站起来
你一定可以再站起来
而且资格考你也合格了
而且资格考你也합格了
之后就能去念大学啦
지后就能去念대학원
我仔细想了很久…
나는 仔细想了很久…
发现这些全都是你造成的
发现这些전체도시是你造成成
这话是什么意思
这话是什么의미思
如果你没有出现
如果你没流现
我也不需要跟哲雄竞争
나는 불공평하다
老实说 比起哲雄挨揍
老实说 比起哲雄挨揍
听到你被英卓打的那瞬间
听到你被英卓打的那瞬间
我就想把他给杀了
我就想把他给杀了
那并不是意外伤害致死
那并不是意外伤害致死
我是真的想杀了他
나는 정말 좋아해요
李斗学
이학
你自以为在拍什么 悲剧爱情电影吗
你自以为는 拍什么에서 悲剧爱情电影吗
我爸过世了 加上我又休学
我爸过世了 加上我又休학
你觉得很抱歉吗
你觉得很抱歉吗
as a murderer You're afraid you'll hinder my future
살인자로서 당신은 내 미래를 방해할까 봐 두려워요
So although you are heartbroken
그러니 마음이 아프더라도
But for my own good Decided to disappear from my life
하지만 내 이익을 위해서 내 인생에서 사라지기로 결심
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
Did I say I wanted to marry you?
내가 당신과 결혼하고 싶다고 말했나요?
If you sympathize with me will make me more miserable
당신이 나와 공감한다면 나를 더 비참하게 만들 거야
you really are...
당신은 정말...
No matter what you say, it doesn't matter to me
네가 무슨 말을 하든 내겐 상관없어
But one thing I'm sure of
하지만 한 가지 확신하는 건
You are a scarier prison than this one
넌 이 감옥보다 더 무서운 감옥이야
Let me go now
이제 가게 해주세요
I'm serious
나는 진지하다
Li Douxue…
리두수에…
(Seoul Jongno)
(서울 종로)
(Celebrating the successful bid for the 1988 Olympic Games)
(1988년 올림픽 유치 성공을 기념)
Down with dictatorship and fight for democracy...
독재 타도하고 민주화 투쟁…
Abominable
혐오스러운
Leave it to me
나에게 맡겨라
Brat...
형님...
catch them
그들을 잡아라
who are you
당신은 누구입니까?
What are you playing?
지금 뭐하고 놀고 있어요?
Take off the gas mask
방독면을 벗으세요
Abominable
혐오스러운
Although I don't know who you are
당신이 누구인지는 모르지만
But thanks anyway
하지만 어쨌든 고마워요
Brother
형
Brother Dou Xue
Error 504 (Server Error)!!1504.That’s an error.There was an error. Please try again later.That’s all we know.
how are you
어떻게 지내세요
Do you really want to be caught and imprisoned?
정말로 잡혀서 감옥에 갇히고 싶나요?
You said you would be responsible for my life, right?
내 인생은 당신이 책임지겠다고 했죠?
You said you would make it up to me when you succeed
성공하면 나한테 보상해주겠다고 했잖아
You brat
이 개자식아
"We wake up while people are still sleeping"
"사람들이 아직 자고 있을 때 우리는 깨어난다"
"The rural children of the Korean nation..."
"조선민족의 시골아이들..."
We visited the prison several times before
우리는 이전에 여러 번 감옥을 방문했습니다.
That's because you are so sentimental
그건 네가 너무 감상적이라서 그래
I didn't promise to meet you.
나는 당신을 만나기로 약속하지 않았습니다.
You have changed a lot
많이 변하셨어요
Where has the simple Li Douxue gone?
단순한 Li Douxue는 어디로 갔습니까?
You don't know the two of us Have positions been reversed?
당신은 우리 둘을 몰라요 입장이 바뀌었나요?
It was my father who owed your family favors.
당신의 가족에게 은혜를 입힌 사람은 내 아버지였습니다.
Now you owe me a favor, right?
이제 나한테 빚진 거 맞죠?
Yes
예
So you start from now on Be my little brother
그럼 지금부터 시작하세요 내 동생이 되어줘
You have to work hard for me
나를 위해 열심히 일해야 해
That's of course
물론이죠
Master, just give me your orders
주인님, 명령만 내리세요
Brat, I'm not kidding you.
형, 농담하는 게 아니예요.
Hello
안녕하세요
You're not allowed to go to any more demonstrations
더 이상 시위에 참석할 수 없습니다.
Preparing for the Bar Exam
변호사 시험 준비
As long as you make up your mind You can pass the judicial examination, right?
당신이 마음만 먹으면 사법시험에 합격할 수 있겠죠?
Become a prosecutor
검사가 되다
Prosecutor?
고발자?
I didn't know until I was in prison
감옥에 있을 때까지는 몰랐어요
Those guys who can kill without even an inch of weapons is the strongest
한 치의 무기도 없어도 사람을 죽일 수 있는 놈들 Error 504 (Server Error)!!1504.That’s an error.There was an error. Please try again later.That’s all we know.
Brother, have you gone back home to have a look?
형님, 집에 가서 구경하셨나요?
How are your uncle and aunt doing?
삼촌과 이모는 어떻게 지내세요?
Zhenyu must have grown up a lot, right?
Zhenyu는 많이 성장 했겠죠?
where do you live now
지금 어디 사세요?
I didn't go home
나는 집에 가지 않았다
My parents are not doing well
부모님이 잘 안계셔
Zhenyu has indeed grown up a lot
진우 진짜 많이 컸네
I live in Seoul now, okay?
나 지금 서울에 살아요, 그렇죠?
This is my address and phone number
이건 내 주소와 전화번호야
Uncle and aunt must miss you very much
삼촌, 이모가 많이 보고 싶겠군요
By the way, I saw Dingchen
그런데 딩첸을 봤어요
She looks like she's had a hard time
그 사람은 힘든 시간을 보낸 것 같아
University is also on leave
대학도 휴학 중
There are rumors that
소문이 있습니다.
Her aunt in Seoul wants to take the theater away
서울에 있는 그녀의 이모는 극장을 다른 곳으로 가져가고 싶어한다
Don't try to avoid me
나를 피하려고 하지마
Why am I hiding from you?
내가 왜 당신에게서 숨어 있습니까?
I'm very happy to see you
만나서 정말 기뻐요
Pass the judicial examination for me before graduation
졸업하기 전에 사법시험에 합격해 주세요
This is the command
이것은 명령이다
What about you?
당신은 어때요?
What are you going to do during this time?
이 시간 동안 무엇을 할 예정인가요?
Monitor you
당신을 모니터링
(Seoul Busan) And let me ask you
(서울 부산) 그리고 물어보자
Your brother...what's his name?
네 동생... 이름이 뭐지?
Shunwan… That's right
순완… 그렇죠
It's Soon Wan
순완이에요
Five sisters and brothers… We are five sisters
다섯 자매와 형제들… 우리는 다섯 자매예요
(Boss Gao Fenghao) That's right, I found someone...
(가오펑하오 사장) 그렇구나, 누군가를 찾았어...
Among the five sisters, there is also a younger sister
다섯 자매 중에는 여동생도 있다.
what's her name
그 사람 이름이 뭐예요?
what What's my sister's name?
뭐 내 여동생 이름이 뭐예요?
But do these guys want to come?
그런데 이 사람들이 오려고 합니까?
(Fudefang)
(푸데팡)
I have my eye on an object
나는 사물을 바라보고 있다
Let’s make a fortune this time through real estate fraud.
이번에는 부동산 사기로 돈을 벌어보자.
Is there any way to get the stuff?
물건 구할 수 있는 방법이 있나요?
Everyone seems to be here
다들 여기 있는 것 같아
Just explain it carefully.
그냥 주의 깊게 설명해보세요.
Wait, there's one more person who hasn't arrived yet.
잠깐, 아직 안 온 사람이 한 명 더 있어요.
The note is coming
쪽지가 옵니다
Come on in
들어와
Come, everyone, gather
자, 모두 모여라
Let me introduce the last member of our team
우리 팀의 마지막 멤버를 소개하겠습니다.
Is it this kid?
이 아이인가요?
(Gao Fenghao, nicknamed Land King) (Head of a real estate fraud group with three previous convictions)
(Gao Fenghao, 별명 Land King) (3차례 전과가 있는 부동산 사기단 대표)
(Chengjin Construction)
(청진건설)
So beautiful. So beautiful.
너무 아름다워요. 너무 아름다워요.
(Zhang Changde is nicknamed Changgan) (The responder has four previous convictions)
(장창덕의 별명은 창간이다) (응답자는 이전에 4번의 유죄 판결을 받았습니다.)
If you want to poop, go home and poop.
똥 싸고 싶으면 집에 가서 똥 싸라.
Have you brought anything?
뭐 가져오셨나요?
Gotta get it back within three days
3일 안에 돌려받아야 해
Got it
알았어요
(House ownership certificate)
(주택소유증명서)
(personal data)
(개인 데이터)
(gift contract)
(선물 계약)
(House ownership certificate)
(주택소유증명서)
(House ownership certificate Li Mingshu)
(주택 소유권 증명서 Li Mingshu)
Hello
안녕하세요
What's wrong
무슨 일이야?
Can you run errands?
심부름을 할 수 있나요?
It was you who asked me to buy apples
나한테 사과 사달라고 한 건 너였어
Eat and see for yourself. Eat and see.
직접 먹고 확인해 보세요. 먹고 보세요.
I told you to buy Fuji apples
후지사과 사오라고 했어
But this is a ruby apple
하지만 이건 루비 사과야
Isn't this... all the same?
이거... 다 똑같지 않아?
Abominable
혐오스러운
Still the elder sister is reliable
그래도 언니는 든든하다
It's obviously the same
분명 똑같은데
You stinky guy
냄새나는 놈아
(House ownership certificate)
(주택소유증명서)
It's so perfect
너무 완벽해요
(Son Soo-gong, Nickname Expert) (Responsible for three previous convictions for document forgery)
(손수공 닉네임 전문가) (문서위조로 3차례 유죄판결을 받은 전과자)
Not bad
나쁘지 않아요
(Ma Qingzi nicknamed pants) (The fake owner has two previous convictions)
(마청자 별명 바지) (가짜 소유자는 이전에 두 번의 유죄 판결을 받았습니다.)
(House ownership certificate)
(주택소유증명서)
(Li Douxue, a guy from nowhere) (Doing all the chores, a previous conviction)
(여기서 온 남자, 리두수) (모든 집안일을 하고, 전과가 있음)
(Nanhai Theater House Ownership Certificate)
(난하이 극장 하우스 소유권 증명서)
Is that okay?
괜찮나요?
If only I had done this earlier We don’t have to use bad words either.
내가 이 일을 더 일찍 했더라면 우리도 나쁜 말을 쓸 필요는 없습니다.
Let's stamp it here too
여기도 스탬프 찍자
(cut book)
(컷북)
Why do we need to sign a divorce agreement?
왜 이혼 합의서에 서명해야 합니까?
As long as you pay off the debt I'll give the theater back to you right away
빚을 갚는 한 극장 바로 돌려드릴께요
That is to say Aunt and niece should trust each other
즉, 이모와 조카는 서로를 믿어야 한다
Maybe other families are like that
아마 다른 가족들도 그럴 것 같아요
But the relationship between our families is extra special
하지만 우리 가족의 관계는 더욱 특별해요
Isn't it?
그렇지 않나요?
aunt uncle
이모 삼촌
You must abide by your agreement with me
나와의 계약을 준수해야 합니다.
Got it...don't worry
알았어...걱정하지 마
By the way, our office has moved.
그런데, 우리 사무실이 이전했습니다.
Jeongjin, if you come to Seoul, please stop by.
정진 씨, 서울에 오시면 꼭 들러주세요.
I will treat you to the Chinese food you like
당신이 좋아하는 중국 음식을 대접해 드리겠습니다
I really can't stand you
난 정말 당신을 참을 수가 없어요
There are rumors that
소문이 있습니다.
Her aunt in Seoul wants to take the theater away
서울에 있는 그녀의 이모는 극장을 다른 곳으로 가져가고 싶어한다
(Representative of Shinil Industries, Zheng Guoyong)
(신일산업 대표 정궈용)
(Preview of next episode)
(다음화 예고)
Do you have an aunt who runs a theater in Gwangju?
광주에서 극장을 운영하는 이모가 있나요?
She's my mom's cousin
그 사람은 우리 엄마의 사촌이야
Get out
나가
Don’t meet Douxue again in the future
앞으로는 두슈를 만나지 마세요
Nothing good will happen if you get involved with him
그 사람이랑 엮이면 좋은 일 없을 거야
Well, I think he seems to have changed
글쎄, 내 생각엔 그 사람이 변한 것 같아
You should hand that to the other party before leaving.
떠나기 전에 상대방에게 그것을 건네주어야 합니다.
(Nanhai Theater House Ownership Certificate) There must be someone else who owns the house
(난하이 극장 하우스 소유권 증명서) 집 주인이 따로 있을 거에요
We should at least have a clear conscience.
우리는 적어도 깨끗한 양심을 가져야 합니다.
Of course, you have to have a clear conscience
물론 깨끗한 양심을 가지고 있어야 합니다.
Even in the worst circumstances
최악의 상황에서도
I also try hard to make myself feel clear
나 또한 내 자신을 맑게 만들려고 노력한다.
what is this place
이곳은 어떤 곳인가요?
Can't you see?
볼 수 없나요?
Brother, do you want to go to Lishui?
형님, 리수이에 가실래요?
You also want to meet Dingchen, right?
당신도 딩첸을 만나고 싶죠?
Brat, you have to go there by yourself
형, 거기는 너 혼자 가야 해